[
{"Front": "遭う", "Back": "あう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "扇ぐ", "Back": "あおぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "青白い", "Back": "あおじろい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明き", "Back": "あき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飽くまで", "Back": "あくまで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "明け方", "Back": "あけがた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揚げる", "Back": "あげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "挙げる", "Back": "あげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憧れる", "Back": "あこがれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "足跡", "Back": "あしあと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "味わう", "Back": "あじわう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "預かる", "Back": "あずかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暖まる", "Back": "あたたまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暖める", "Back": "あたためる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "あひら", "Back": "あひら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "厚かましい", "Back": "あつかましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "圧縮", "Back": "あっしゅく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宛名", "Back": "あてな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "暴れる", "Back": "あばれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脂", "Back": "あぶら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雨戸", "Back": "あまど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "甘やかす", "Back": "あまやかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余る", "Back": "あまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "編物", "Back": "あみもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "編む", "Back": "あむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "危うい", "Back": "あやうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怪しい", "Back": "あやしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "荒い", "Back": "あらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粗い", "Back": "あらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "争う", "Back": "あらそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改めて", "Back": "あらためて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改める", "Back": "あらためる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "著す", "Back": "あらわす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有難い", "Back": "ありがたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "在る", "Back": "ある", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "安易", "Back": "あんい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "案外", "Back": "あんがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言い出す", "Back": "いいだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言い付ける", "Back": "いいつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意義", "Back": "いぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生き生き", "Back": "いきいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "育児", "Back": "いくじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幾分", "Back": "いくぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生け花", "Back": "いけばな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "以後", "Back": "いご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "以降", "Back": "いこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勇ましい", "Back": "いさましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "衣食住", "Back": "いしょくじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "意地悪", "Back": "いじわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一応", "Back": "いちおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一段と", "Back": "いちだんと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一流", "Back": "いちりゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "佚", "Back": "いつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一昨日", "Back": "いっさくじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一昨年", "Back": "いっさくねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一斉", "Back": "いっせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一旦", "Back": "いったん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一定", "Back": "いってい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "移転", "Back": "いてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "井戸", "Back": "いど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "緯度", "Back": "いど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "従姉妹", "Back": "いとこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "威張る", "Back": "いばる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嫌がる", "Back": "いやがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煎る", "Back": "いる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "炒る", "Back": "いる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入れ物", "Back": "いれもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引力", "Back": "いんりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "植木", "Back": "うえき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飢える", "Back": "うえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浮ぶ", "Back": "うかぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浮かべる", "Back": "うかべる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浮く", "Back": "うく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "承る", "Back": "うけたまわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受取", "Back": "うけとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受け持つ", "Back": "うけもつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "薄暗い", "Back": "うすぐらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "薄める", "Back": "うすめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打合せ", "Back": "うちあわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "打ち消す", "Back": "うちけす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "討つ", "Back": "うつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "映す", "Back": "うつす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "写る", "Back": "うつる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "映る", "Back": "うつる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有無", "Back": "うむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "埋める", "Back": "うめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敬う", "Back": "うやまう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裏返す", "Back": "うらがえす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裏口", "Back": "うらぐち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "占う", "Back": "うらなう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恨み", "Back": "うらみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恨む", "Back": "うらむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "羨ましい", "Back": "うらやましい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "羨む", "Back": "うらやむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売上", "Back": "うりあげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売り切れ", "Back": "うりきれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売り切れる", "Back": "うりきれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売行き", "Back": "うれゆき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "運河", "Back": "うんが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "英文", "Back": "えいぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "英和", "Back": "えいわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "液体", "Back": "えきたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絵の具", "Back": "えのぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偉い", "Back": "えらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宴会", "Back": "えんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "園芸", "Back": "えんげい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "演劇", "Back": "えんげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "円周", "Back": "えんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遠足", "Back": "えんそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "延長", "Back": "えんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煙突", "Back": "えんとつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追い掛ける", "Back": "おいかける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追い越す", "Back": "おいこす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "応援", "Back": "おうえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "王女", "Back": "おうじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "応ずる", "Back": "おうずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "応接", "Back": "おうせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "応対", "Back": "おうたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "往復", "Back": "おうふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欧米", "Back": "おうべい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "応用", "Back": "おうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大通り", "Back": "おおどおり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大凡", "Back": "おおよそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お帰り", "Back": "おかえり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拝む", "Back": "おがむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お代わり", "Back": "おかわり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "補う", "Back": "おぎなう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "屋外", "Back": "おくがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "送り仮名", "Back": "おくりがな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "怠る", "Back": "おこたる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "押える", "Back": "おさえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "納める", "Back": "おさめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "治める", "Back": "おさめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "惜しい", "Back": "おしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御辞儀", "Back": "おじぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伯父さん", "Back": "おじさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小父さん", "Back": "おじさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "叔父さん", "Back": "おじさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教わる", "Back": "おそわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落着く", "Back": "おちつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御手洗", "Back": "おてあらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お出掛け", "Back": "おでかけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お手伝いさん", "Back": "おてつだいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落し物", "Back": "おとしもの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "驚かす", "Back": "おどろかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "各々", "Back": "おのおの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伯母さん", "Back": "おばさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "叔母さん", "Back": "おばさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "お参り", "Back": "おまいり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思い掛けない", "Back": "おもいがけない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思い込む", "Back": "おもいこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思いっ切り", "Back": "おもいっきり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "思い付く", "Back": "おもいつく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重たい", "Back": "おもたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "親指", "Back": "おやゆび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "卸す", "Back": "おろす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恩恵", "Back": "おんけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "温室", "Back": "おんしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "温泉", "Back": "おんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "温帯", "Back": "おんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御中", "Back": "おんちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "女の人", "Back": "おんなのひと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蚊", "Back": "か", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貝", "Back": "かい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "開会", "Back": "かいかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "会館", "Back": "かいかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改札", "Back": "かいさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解散", "Back": "かいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "海水浴", "Back": "かいすいよく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回数", "Back": "かいすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回数券", "Back": "かいすうけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改正", "Back": "かいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "快晴", "Back": "かいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解説", "Back": "かいせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "改造", "Back": "かいぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "開通", "Back": "かいつう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回転", "Back": "かいてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解答", "Back": "かいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回答", "Back": "かいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外部", "Back": "がいぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "解放", "Back": "かいほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "開放", "Back": "かいほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "海洋", "Back": "かいよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "概論", "Back": "がいろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "帰す", "Back": "かえす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "却って", "Back": "かえって", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代える", "Back": "かえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反る", "Back": "かえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家屋", "Back": "かおく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "係わる", "Back": "かかわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書留", "Back": "かきとめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書取", "Back": "かきとり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "垣根", "Back": "かきね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掻く", "Back": "かく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "嗅ぐ", "Back": "かぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "架空", "Back": "かくう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "各自", "Back": "かくじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拡充", "Back": "かくじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学術", "Back": "がくじゅつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "各地", "Back": "かくち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拡張", "Back": "かくちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "角度", "Back": "かくど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学年", "Back": "がくねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学部", "Back": "がくぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "格別", "Back": "かくべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "確率", "Back": "かくりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学力", "Back": "がくりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掛け算", "Back": "かけざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "可決", "Back": "かけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火口", "Back": "かこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下降", "Back": "かこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重なる", "Back": "かさなる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重ねる", "Back": "かさねる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飾り", "Back": "かざり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火山", "Back": "かざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貸し出し", "Back": "かしだし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過失", "Back": "かしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "果実", "Back": "かじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貸間", "Back": "かしま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貸家", "Back": "かしや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "個所", "Back": "かしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過剰", "Back": "かじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "課税", "Back": "かぜい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下線", "Back": "かせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加速", "Back": "かそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加速度", "Back": "かそくど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "固い", "Back": "かたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "堅い", "Back": "かたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "片仮名", "Back": "かたかな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "片付く", "Back": "かたづく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塊", "Back": "かたまり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "固まる", "Back": "かたまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "片道", "Back": "かたみち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傾く", "Back": "かたむく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "片寄る", "Back": "かたよる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学科", "Back": "がっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学会", "Back": "がっかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "楽器", "Back": "がっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "学級", "Back": "がっきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "担ぐ", "Back": "かつぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "括弧", "Back": "かっこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "活字", "Back": "かつじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "活躍", "Back": "かつやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "活力", "Back": "かつりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仮定", "Back": "かてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過程", "Back": "かてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "課程", "Back": "かてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仮名", "Back": "かな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仮名遣い", "Back": "かなづかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鐘", "Back": "かね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "加熱", "Back": "かねつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兼ねる", "Back": "かねる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "過半数", "Back": "かはんすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "被せる", "Back": "かぶせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "釜", "Back": "かま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紙屑", "Back": "かみくず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "神様", "Back": "かみさま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "剃刀", "Back": "かみそり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貨物", "Back": "かもつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歌謡", "Back": "かよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殻", "Back": "から", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空っぽ", "Back": "からっぽ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "枯れる", "Back": "かれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乾かす", "Back": "かわかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "渇く", "Back": "かわく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "為替", "Back": "かわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瓦", "Back": "かわら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代る", "Back": "かわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間隔", "Back": "かんかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "換気", "Back": "かんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感激", "Back": "かんげき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "関西", "Back": "かんさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鑑賞", "Back": "かんしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感ずる", "Back": "かんずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間接", "Back": "かんせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乾燥", "Back": "かんそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "感想", "Back": "かんそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観測", "Back": "かんそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寒帯", "Back": "かんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "官庁", "Back": "かんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勘違い", "Back": "かんちがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "缶詰", "Back": "かんづめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乾電池", "Back": "かんでんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "関東", "Back": "かんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "観念", "Back": "かんねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乾杯", "Back": "かんぱい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "看板", "Back": "かんばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "看病", "Back": "かんびょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冠", "Back": "かんむり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漢和", "Back": "かんわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気圧", "Back": "きあつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "器械", "Back": "きかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着替え", "Back": "きがえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "機関車", "Back": "きかんしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飢饉", "Back": "ききん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "器具", "Back": "きぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "期限", "Back": "きげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "記号", "Back": "きごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刻む", "Back": "きざむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "儀式", "Back": "ぎしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基準", "Back": "きじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "規準", "Back": "きじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "起床", "Back": "きしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着せる", "Back": "きせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基礎", "Back": "きそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気体", "Back": "きたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基地", "Back": "きち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "基盤", "Back": "きばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "客席", "Back": "きゃくせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "客間", "Back": "きゃくま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休業", "Back": "きゅうぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休講", "Back": "きゅうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休息", "Back": "きゅうそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "給与", "Back": "きゅうよ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "休養", "Back": "きゅうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清い", "Back": "きよい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強化", "Back": "きょうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "境界", "Back": "きょうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行事", "Back": "ぎょうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恐縮", "Back": "きょうしゅく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "教養", "Back": "きょうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "行列", "Back": "ぎょうれつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漁業", "Back": "ぎょぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "曲線", "Back": "きょくせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "規律", "Back": "きりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "斬る", "Back": "きる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気を付ける", "Back": "きをつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "金魚", "Back": "きんぎょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区域", "Back": "くいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "偶数", "Back": "ぐうすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空想", "Back": "くうそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "空中", "Back": "くうちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "釘", "Back": "くぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区切る", "Back": "くぎる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "櫛", "Back": "くし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苦情", "Back": "くじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "苦心", "Back": "くしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "屑", "Back": "くず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "崩す", "Back": "くずす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "薬指", "Back": "くすりゆび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "崩れる", "Back": "くずれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "砕く", "Back": "くだく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "砕ける", "Back": "くだける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下る", "Back": "くだる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "唇", "Back": "くちびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "口紅", "Back": "くちべに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "句読点", "Back": "くとうてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "配る", "Back": "くばる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "工夫", "Back": "くふう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "区分", "Back": "くぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組合せ", "Back": "くみあわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "組み立てる", "Back": "くみたてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汲む", "Back": "くむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酌む", "Back": "くむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悔しい", "Back": "くやしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悔やむ", "Back": "くやむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "咥える", "Back": "くわえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "郡", "Back": "ぐん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "稽古", "Back": "けいこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敬語", "Back": "けいご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蛍光灯", "Back": "けいこうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "形式", "Back": "けいしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "継続", "Back": "けいぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "毛糸", "Back": "けいと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "経度", "Back": "けいど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "系統", "Back": "けいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "芸能", "Back": "げいのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "競馬", "Back": "けいば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "警備", "Back": "けいび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "形容詞", "Back": "けいようし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "形容動詞", "Back": "けいようどうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外科", "Back": "げか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "毛皮", "Back": "けがわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "激増", "Back": "げきぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下車", "Back": "げしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下旬", "Back": "げじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下水", "Back": "げすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "削る", "Back": "けずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "桁", "Back": "けた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下駄", "Back": "げた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "血圧", "Back": "けつあつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "血液", "Back": "けつえき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月給", "Back": "げっきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傑作", "Back": "けっさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月末", "Back": "げつまつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "気配", "Back": "けはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下品", "Back": "げひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煙い", "Back": "けむい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蹴る", "Back": "ける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "けれど/けれども", "Back": "", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "険しい", "Back": "けわしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見学", "Back": "けんがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "謙虚", "Back": "けんきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原稿", "Back": "げんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原産", "Back": "げんさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原始", "Back": "げんし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "研修", "Back": "けんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "厳重", "Back": "げんじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "謙遜", "Back": "けんそん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "県庁", "Back": "けんちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "限度", "Back": "げんど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "現に", "Back": "げんに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "顕微鏡", "Back": "けんびきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原理", "Back": "げんり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "原料", "Back": "げんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "碁", "Back": "ご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恋しい", "Back": "こいしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "請う", "Back": "こう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "工員", "Back": "こういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強引", "Back": "ごういん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公害", "Back": "こうがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高級", "Back": "こうきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公共", "Back": "こうきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "工芸", "Back": "こうげい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "孝行", "Back": "こうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交差", "Back": "こうさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "講師", "Back": "こうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "工事", "Back": "こうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公式", "Back": "こうしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "口実", "Back": "こうじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "こうして", "Back": "こうして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "校舎", "Back": "こうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公衆", "Back": "こうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "香水", "Back": "こうすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公正", "Back": "こうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "功績", "Back": "こうせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "光線", "Back": "こうせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高層", "Back": "こうそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "構造", "Back": "こうぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交替", "Back": "こうたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "耕地", "Back": "こうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交通機関", "Back": "こうつうきかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "校庭", "Back": "こうてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肯定", "Back": "こうてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高度", "Back": "こうど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高等", "Back": "こうとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合同", "Back": "ごうどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "後輩", "Back": "こうはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公表", "Back": "こうひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉱物", "Back": "こうぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "公務", "Back": "こうむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "項目", "Back": "こうもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紅葉", "Back": "こうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合理", "Back": "ごうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交流", "Back": "こうりゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "合流", "Back": "ごうりゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "効力", "Back": "こうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "超える", "Back": "こえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "焦がす", "Back": "こがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国王", "Back": "こくおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国籍", "Back": "こくせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "国立", "Back": "こくりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "焦げる", "Back": "こげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凍える", "Back": "こごえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心当たり", "Back": "こころあたり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心得る", "Back": "こころえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腰掛け", "Back": "こしかけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "腰掛ける", "Back": "こしかける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "五十音", "Back": "ごじゅうおん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "胡椒", "Back": "こしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "超す", "Back": "こす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "擦る", "Back": "こする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "個体", "Back": "こたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御馳走", "Back": "ごちそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小遣い", "Back": "こづかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "古典", "Back": "こてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "琴", "Back": "こと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言付ける", "Back": "ことづける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "言葉遣い", "Back": "ことばづかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御無沙汰", "Back": "ごぶさた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塵芥", "Back": "ごみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御免", "Back": "ごめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小指", "Back": "こゆび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "娯楽", "Back": "ごらく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "御覧", "Back": "ごらん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転がす", "Back": "ころがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転がる", "Back": "ころがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紺", "Back": "こん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混合", "Back": "こんごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "献立", "Back": "こんだて", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "在学", "Back": "ざいがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再三", "Back": "さいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祭日", "Back": "さいじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "催促", "Back": "さいそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "採点", "Back": "さいてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "災難", "Back": "さいなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裁縫", "Back": "さいほう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "材木", "Back": "ざいもく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逆さ", "Back": "さかさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逆様", "Back": "さかさま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捜す", "Back": "さがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遡る", "Back": "さかのぼる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酒場", "Back": "さかば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先程", "Back": "さきほど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "裂く", "Back": "さく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "索引", "Back": "さくいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作者", "Back": "さくしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "削除", "Back": "さくじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作成", "Back": "さくせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作製", "Back": "さくせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "探る", "Back": "さぐる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "囁く", "Back": "ささやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刺さる", "Back": "ささる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "匙", "Back": "さじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "座敷", "Back": "ざしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差し支え", "Back": "さしつかえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "差し引き", "Back": "さしひき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刺身", "Back": "さしみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刺す", "Back": "さす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "挿す", "Back": "さす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "注す", "Back": "さす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "射す", "Back": "さす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流石", "Back": "さすが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "撮影", "Back": "さつえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雑音", "Back": "ざつおん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "早速", "Back": "さっそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "錆", "Back": "さび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "錆びる", "Back": "さびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "座布団", "Back": "ざぶとん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷ます", "Back": "さます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "妨げる", "Back": "さまたげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷める", "Back": "さめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再来月", "Back": "さらいげつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再来週", "Back": "さらいしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "再来年", "Back": "さらいねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "騒がしい", "Back": "さわがしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "三角", "Back": "さんかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "算数", "Back": "さんすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酸性", "Back": "さんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "産地", "Back": "さんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "山林", "Back": "さんりん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仕上がる", "Back": "しあがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寺院", "Back": "じいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "しいんと", "Back": "（する）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自衛", "Back": "じえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塩辛い", "Back": "しおからい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "司会", "Back": "しかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "四角", "Back": "しかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "四角い", "Back": "しかくい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "時間割", "Back": "じかんわり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "四季", "Back": "しき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敷地", "Back": "しきち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "至急", "Back": "しきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "敷く", "Back": "しく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "茂る", "Back": "しげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "持参", "Back": "じさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "磁石", "Back": "じしゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "四捨五入", "Back": "ししゃごにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "始終", "Back": "しじゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自習", "Back": "じしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "静まる", "Back": "しずまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "姿勢", "Back": "しせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自然科学", "Back": "しぜんかがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "時速", "Back": "じそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "子孫", "Back": "しそん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "死体", "Back": "したい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下書き", "Back": "したがき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "下町", "Back": "したまち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "自治", "Back": "じち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実感", "Back": "じっかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "湿気", "Back": "しっけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実習", "Back": "じっしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実績", "Back": "じっせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "湿度", "Back": "しつど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "執筆", "Back": "しっぴつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実物", "Back": "じつぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実用", "Back": "じつよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実力", "Back": "じつりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実例", "Back": "じつれい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "失恋", "Back": "しつれん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "指定", "Back": "してい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "私鉄", "Back": "してつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "児童", "Back": "じどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縛る", "Back": "しばる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地盤", "Back": "じばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紙幣", "Back": "しへい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絞る", "Back": "しぼる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縞", "Back": "しま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地味", "Back": "じみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "氏名", "Back": "しめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "締切", "Back": "しめきり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "締め切る", "Back": "しめきる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "湿る", "Back": "しめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "社会科学", "Back": "しゃかいかがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蛇口", "Back": "じゃぐち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "弱点", "Back": "じゃくてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "車庫", "Back": "しゃこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "車掌", "Back": "しゃしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "写生", "Back": "しゃせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "社説", "Back": "しゃせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "車輪", "Back": "しゃりん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "洒落", "Back": "しゃれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "集会", "Back": "しゅうかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "住居", "Back": "じゅうきょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "集金", "Back": "しゅうきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "集合", "Back": "しゅうごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "習字", "Back": "しゅうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "修繕", "Back": "しゅうぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重体", "Back": "じゅうたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "じゅうたん", "Back": "（カーペット）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "終点", "Back": "しゅうてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重点", "Back": "じゅうてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "就任", "Back": "しゅうにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "周辺", "Back": "しゅうへん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重役", "Back": "じゅうやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "終了", "Back": "しゅうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重量", "Back": "じゅうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "重力", "Back": "じゅうりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "熟語", "Back": "じゅくご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祝日", "Back": "しゅくじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縮小", "Back": "しゅくしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受験", "Back": "じゅけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主語", "Back": "しゅご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出勤", "Back": "しゅっきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "述語", "Back": "じゅつご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出張", "Back": "しゅっちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寿命", "Back": "じゅみょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "主役", "Back": "しゅやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "受話器", "Back": "じゅわき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "循環", "Back": "じゅんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巡査", "Back": "じゅんさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "順々", "Back": "じゅんじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "順序", "Back": "じゅんじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "純情", "Back": "じゅんじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "純粋", "Back": "じゅんすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消化", "Back": "しょうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小学生", "Back": "しょうがくせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "将棋", "Back": "しょうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蒸気", "Back": "じょうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定規", "Back": "じょうぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上級", "Back": "じょうきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "商業", "Back": "しょうぎょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消極的", "Back": "しょうきょくてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賞金", "Back": "しょうきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上下", "Back": "じょうげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "障子", "Back": "しょうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "商社", "Back": "しょうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乗車", "Back": "じょうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上旬", "Back": "じょうじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生ずる", "Back": "しょうずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小数", "Back": "しょうすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "商店", "Back": "しょうてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "焦点", "Back": "しょうてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消毒", "Back": "しょうどく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勝敗", "Back": "しょうはい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蒸発", "Back": "じょうはつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "賞品", "Back": "しょうひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "勝負", "Back": "しょうぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "小便", "Back": "しょうべん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消防署", "Back": "しょうぼうしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正味", "Back": "しょうみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正面", "Back": "しょうめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "消耗", "Back": "しょうもう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "醤油", "Back": "しょうゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "省略", "Back": "しょうりゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "初級", "Back": "しょきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助教授", "Back": "じょきょうじゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食塩", "Back": "しょくえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "職人", "Back": "しょくにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "初旬", "Back": "しょじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書籍", "Back": "しょせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "食器", "Back": "しょっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書店", "Back": "しょてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "書道", "Back": "しょどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "白髪", "Back": "しらが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知合い", "Back": "しりあい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "私立", "Back": "しりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "資料", "Back": "しりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汁", "Back": "しる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素人", "Back": "しろうと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "芯", "Back": "しん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "新幹線", "Back": "しんかんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真空", "Back": "しんくう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "信ずる", "Back": "しんずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "心身", "Back": "しんしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申請", "Back": "しんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人造", "Back": "じんぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寝台", "Back": "しんだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "診断", "Back": "しんだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "侵入", "Back": "しんにゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人文科学", "Back": "じんぶんかがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人命", "Back": "じんめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "深夜", "Back": "しんや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "森林", "Back": "しんりん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "親類", "Back": "しんるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "針路", "Back": "しんろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "神話", "Back": "しんわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酢", "Back": "す", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水産", "Back": "すいさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "炊事", "Back": "すいじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水蒸気", "Back": "すいじょうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水素", "Back": "すいそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "垂直", "Back": "すいちょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "推定", "Back": "すいてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水滴", "Back": "すいてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水筒", "Back": "すいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "随筆", "Back": "ずいひつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水分", "Back": "すいぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水平", "Back": "すいへい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水平線", "Back": "すいへいせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "水曜", "Back": "すいよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "末っ子", "Back": "すえっこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "図鑑", "Back": "ずかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "杉", "Back": "すぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好き嫌い", "Back": "すききらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "好き好き", "Back": "すきずき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "透き通る", "Back": "すきとおる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "隙間", "Back": "すきま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "図形", "Back": "ずけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鈴", "Back": "すず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "涼む", "Back": "すずむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "棄てる", "Back": "すてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素直", "Back": "すなお", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頭脳", "Back": "ずのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "図表", "Back": "ずひょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "住まい", "Back": "すまい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "墨", "Back": "すみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "澄む", "Back": "すむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清む", "Back": "すむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相撲", "Back": "すもう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掏摸", "Back": "すり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "刷る", "Back": "する", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "狡い", "Back": "ずるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滑れる", "Back": "ずれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寸法", "Back": "すんぽう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "姓", "Back": "せい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "税関", "Back": "ぜいかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "製作", "Back": "せいさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "制作", "Back": "せいさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "性質", "Back": "せいしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清書", "Back": "せいしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "青少年", "Back": "せいしょうねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "整数", "Back": "せいすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "清掃", "Back": "せいそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生存", "Back": "せいぞん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生長", "Back": "せいちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "政党", "Back": "せいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生年月日", "Back": "せいねんがっぴ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "性能", "Back": "せいのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "整備", "Back": "せいび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成分", "Back": "せいぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "性別", "Back": "せいべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正方形", "Back": "せいほうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "正門", "Back": "せいもん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "成立", "Back": "せいりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "西暦", "Back": "せいれき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "背負う", "Back": "せおう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "赤道", "Back": "せきどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "折角", "Back": "せっかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "接近", "Back": "せっきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "石鹸", "Back": "せっけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "接する", "Back": "せっする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "接続", "Back": "せつぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瀬戸物", "Back": "せともの", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "迫る", "Back": "せまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "攻める", "Back": "せめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "栓", "Back": "せん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "前後", "Back": "ぜんご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "洗剤", "Back": "せんざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全集", "Back": "ぜんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全身", "Back": "ぜんしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "扇子", "Back": "せんす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "専制", "Back": "せんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先々月", "Back": "せんせんげつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先々週", "Back": "せんせんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先祖", "Back": "せんぞ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先端", "Back": "せんたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "宣伝", "Back": "せんでん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "先頭", "Back": "せんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "全般", "Back": "ぜんぱん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "扇風機", "Back": "せんぷうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "線路", "Back": "せんろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相違", "Back": "そうい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "雑巾", "Back": "ぞうきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "増減", "Back": "ぞうげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "倉庫", "Back": "そうこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "相互", "Back": "そうご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "創作", "Back": "そうさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "葬式", "Back": "そうしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "造船", "Back": "ぞうせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "騒々しい", "Back": "そうぞうしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "増大", "Back": "ぞうだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "送別", "Back": "そうべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "草履", "Back": "ぞうり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "総理大臣", "Back": "そうりだいじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "送料", "Back": "そうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "属する", "Back": "ぞくする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "続々", "Back": "ぞくぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "速達", "Back": "そくたつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "測定", "Back": "そくてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "測量", "Back": "そくりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "速力", "Back": "そくりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "素質", "Back": "そしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祖先", "Back": "そせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "卒直", "Back": "そっちょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "具える", "Back": "そなえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蕎麦", "Back": "そば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "剃る", "Back": "そる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逸れる", "Back": "それる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揃う", "Back": "そろう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揃える", "Back": "そろえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "算盤", "Back": "そろばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "存じる", "Back": "ぞんじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "存ずる", "Back": "ぞんずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "損得", "Back": "そんとく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "田ぼ", "Back": "たんぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "だいいち", "Back": "（副）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退院", "Back": "たいいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大学院", "Back": "だいがくいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大工", "Back": "だいく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体系", "Back": "たいけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "太鼓", "Back": "たいこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対策", "Back": "たいさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大して", "Back": "たいして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "対照", "Back": "たいしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大小", "Back": "だいしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体制", "Back": "たいせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体積", "Back": "たいせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大層", "Back": "たいそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "体操", "Back": "たいそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大分", "Back": "だいぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "大木", "Back": "たいぼく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "題名", "Back": "だいめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "代名詞", "Back": "だいめいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "Ͼ立", "Back": "たいりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "田植え", "Back": "たうえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "絶えず", "Back": "たえず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "楕円", "Back": "だえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "高める", "Back": "たかめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "耕す", "Back": "たがやす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "滝", "Back": "たき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "炊く", "Back": "たく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "焚く", "Back": "たく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蓄える", "Back": "たくわえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "竹", "Back": "たけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "助かる", "Back": "たすかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "只", "Back": "ただ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "但し", "Back": "ただし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "畳む", "Back": "たたむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "立ち止まる", "Back": "たちどまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "建つ", "Back": "たつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発つ", "Back": "たつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "脱線", "Back": "だっせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "妥当", "Back": "だとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "例える", "Back": "たとえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頼もしい", "Back": "たのもしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "足袋", "Back": "たび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溜まる", "Back": "たまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溜息", "Back": "ためいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溜める", "Back": "ためる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "足る", "Back": "たる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "段階", "Back": "だんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "短期", "Back": "たんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "炭鉱", "Back": "たんこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "短所", "Back": "たんしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "淡水", "Back": "たんすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "断水", "Back": "だんすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "単数", "Back": "たんすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "団地", "Back": "だんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "断定", "Back": "だんてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "短編", "Back": "たんぺん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "誓う", "Back": "ちかう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地下水", "Back": "ちかすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近々", "Back": "ちかぢか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近付ける", "Back": "ちかづける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "近寄る", "Back": "ちかよる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "力強い", "Back": "ちからづよい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地質", "Back": "ちしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "知人", "Back": "ちじん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地帯", "Back": "ちたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縮む", "Back": "ちぢむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縮める", "Back": "ちぢめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縮れる", "Back": "ちぢれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地点", "Back": "ちてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "地名", "Back": "ちめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "茶色い", "Back": "ちゃいろい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着々", "Back": "ちゃくちゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "茶碗", "Back": "ちゃわん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中間", "Back": "ちゅうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中旬", "Back": "ちゅうじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "抽象", "Back": "ちゅうしょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中世", "Back": "ちゅうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中性", "Back": "ちゅうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中途", "Back": "ちゅうと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中年", "Back": "ちゅうねん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "超過", "Back": "ちょうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "彫刻", "Back": "ちょうこく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長所", "Back": "ちょうしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長女", "Back": "ちょうじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調整", "Back": "ちょうせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調節", "Back": "ちょうせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長短", "Back": "ちょうたん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "頂点", "Back": "ちょうてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長男", "Back": "ちょうなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長方形", "Back": "ちょうほうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "調味料", "Back": "ちょうみりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直後", "Back": "ちょくご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直線", "Back": "ちょくせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直前", "Back": "ちょくぜん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直通", "Back": "ちょくつう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直流", "Back": "ちょくりゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "貯蔵", "Back": "ちょぞう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直角", "Back": "ちょっかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "直径", "Back": "ちょっけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "散らかす", "Back": "ちらかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "散らかる", "Back": "ちらかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "散らす", "Back": "ちらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塵紙", "Back": "ちりがみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "散る", "Back": "ちる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "追加", "Back": "ついか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通貨", "Back": "つうか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通勤", "Back": "つうきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通ずる", "Back": "つうずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通知", "Back": "つうち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通帳", "Back": "つうちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通訳", "Back": "つうやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通用", "Back": "つうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通路", "Back": "つうろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付合う", "Back": "つきあう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突き当たり", "Back": "つきあたり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突き当たる", "Back": "つきあたる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "月日", "Back": "つきひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "点く", "Back": "つく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突く", "Back": "つく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "次ぐ", "Back": "つぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "作る/造る", "Back": "つくる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "着ける", "Back": "つける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "点ける", "Back": "つける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浸ける", "Back": "つける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伝わる", "Back": "つたわる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "突っ込む", "Back": "つっこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "務める", "Back": "つとめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "努める", "Back": "つとめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "綱", "Back": "つな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繋がり", "Back": "つながり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繋がる", "Back": "つながる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "繋げる", "Back": "つなげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "粒", "Back": "つぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "潰す", "Back": "つぶす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "潰れる", "Back": "つぶれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詰まる", "Back": "つまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "積む", "Back": "つむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "爪", "Back": "つめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "艶", "Back": "つや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "強気", "Back": "つよき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "釣り合う", "Back": "つりあう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吊る", "Back": "つる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吊す", "Back": "つるす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出合い", "Back": "であい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手洗い", "Back": "てあらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定員", "Back": "ていいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定価", "Back": "ていか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "低下", "Back": "ていか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定期券", "Back": "ていきけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "定休日", "Back": "ていきゅうび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "停止", "Back": "ていし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "停車", "Back": "ていしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "停電", "Back": "ていでん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出入り", "Back": "でいり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出入口", "Back": "でいりぐち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手入れ", "Back": "ていれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出掛ける", "Back": "でかける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出来上がり", "Back": "できあがり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出来上がる", "Back": "できあがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "的確", "Back": "てきかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "適確", "Back": "てきかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手首", "Back": "てくび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凸凹", "Back": "でこぼこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手頃", "Back": "てごろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手帳", "Back": "てちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉄橋", "Back": "てっきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手続き", "Back": "てつづき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉄砲", "Back": "てっぽう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手拭い", "Back": "てぬぐい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "手前", "Back": "てまえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出迎え", "Back": "でむかえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "出迎える", "Back": "でむかえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "照らす", "Back": "てらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "照る", "Back": "てる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "展開", "Back": "てんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伝記", "Back": "でんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電球", "Back": "でんきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "点数", "Back": "てんすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "伝染", "Back": "でんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電池", "Back": "でんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "点々", "Back": "てんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "転々", "Back": "てんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電柱", "Back": "でんちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "天皇", "Back": "てんのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電波", "Back": "でんぱ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電流", "Back": "でんりゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "電力", "Back": "でんりょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "問い合わせ", "Back": "といあわせ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "銅", "Back": "どう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "統一", "Back": "とういつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "同格", "Back": "どうかく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "峠", "Back": "とうげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "統計", "Back": "とうけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "動作", "Back": "どうさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "東西", "Back": "とうざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当日", "Back": "とうじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "投書", "Back": "とうしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "登場", "Back": "とうじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "灯台", "Back": "とうだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盗難", "Back": "とうなん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "当番", "Back": "とうばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "等分", "Back": "とうぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "透明", "Back": "とうめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "灯油", "Back": "とうゆ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "東洋", "Back": "とうよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "童話", "Back": "どうわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "通り掛かる", "Back": "とおりかかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溶かす", "Back": "とかす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "尖る", "Back": "とがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溶く", "Back": "とく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退く", "Back": "どく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特殊", "Back": "とくしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特色", "Back": "とくしょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特長", "Back": "とくちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特定", "Back": "とくてい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "特売", "Back": "とくばい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溶け込む", "Back": "とけこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溶ける", "Back": "とける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "退ける", "Back": "どける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "床の間", "Back": "とこのま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "床屋", "Back": "とこや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "所々", "Back": "ところどころ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "都心", "Back": "としん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "戸棚", "Back": "とだな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "整う", "Back": "ととのう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "留まる", "Back": "とどまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "飛び込む", "Back": "とびこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "跳ぶ", "Back": "とぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "泊める", "Back": "とめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捕える", "Back": "とらえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り入れる", "Back": "とりいれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り消す", "Back": "とりけす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "取り出す", "Back": "とりだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "採る", "Back": "とる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捕る", "Back": "とる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "丼", "Back": "どんぶり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内科", "Back": "ないか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "内線", "Back": "ないせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "治す", "Back": "なおす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "永い", "Back": "ながい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仲直り", "Back": "なかなおり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "長引く", "Back": "ながびく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中身", "Back": "なかみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中味", "Back": "なかみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "中指", "Back": "なかゆび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "仲良し", "Back": "なかよし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慰める", "Back": "なぐさめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "亡くす", "Back": "なくす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "為す", "Back": "なす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "謎謎", "Back": "なぞなぞ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "傾らか", "Back": "なだらか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "懐かしい", "Back": "なつかしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "撫でる", "Back": "なでる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "斜め", "Back": "ななめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何々", "Back": "なになに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "何分", "Back": "なにぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生意気", "Back": "なまいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "並木", "Back": "なみき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "倣う", "Back": "ならう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鳴らす", "Back": "ならす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生る", "Back": "なる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "馴れる", "Back": "なれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "南極", "Back": "なんきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "南米", "Back": "なんべい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "南北", "Back": "なんぼく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煮える", "Back": "にえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "匂う", "Back": "におう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "逃がす", "Back": "にがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憎い", "Back": "にくい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憎む", "Back": "にくむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "憎らしい", "Back": "にくらしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濁る", "Back": "にごる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "虹", "Back": "にじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日時", "Back": "にちじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日用品", "Back": "にちようひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日課", "Back": "にっか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日程", "Back": "にってい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鈍い", "Back": "にぶい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "入社", "Back": "にゅうしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "女房", "Back": "にょうぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "睨む", "Back": "にらむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煮る", "Back": "にる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "俄", "Back": "にわか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "縫う", "Back": "ぬう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濡らす", "Back": "ぬらす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "熱する", "Back": "ねっする", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捩る", "Back": "ねじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寝間着", "Back": "ねまき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寝巻", "Back": "ねまき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "狙う", "Back": "ねらう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "狙い", "Back": "ねらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "年度", "Back": "ねんど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農産物", "Back": "のうさんぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農村", "Back": "のうそん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "濃度", "Back": "のうど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "農薬", "Back": "のうやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "能率", "Back": "のうりつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "残らず", "Back": "のこらず", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "載せる", "Back": "のせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "覗く", "Back": "のぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "延ばす", "Back": "のばす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "延びる", "Back": "のびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上り", "Back": "のぼり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "上る", "Back": "のぼる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "糊", "Back": "のり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乗換", "Back": "のりかえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "載る", "Back": "のる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呑気", "Back": "のんき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "灰色", "Back": "はいいろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "俳句", "Back": "はいく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拝見", "Back": "はいけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売店", "Back": "ばいてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "売買", "Back": "ばいばい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "這う", "Back": "はう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "生える", "Back": "はえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "剥す", "Back": "はがす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "秤", "Back": "はかり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "量る", "Back": "はかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "測る", "Back": "はかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吐き気", "Back": "はきけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掃く", "Back": "はく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歯車", "Back": "はぐるま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "挟まる", "Back": "はさまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "挟む", "Back": "はさむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "箸", "Back": "はし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "梯子", "Back": "はしご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "始めに", "Back": "はじめに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "初めに", "Back": "はじめに", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "斜", "Back": "はす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "外れる", "Back": "はずれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肌着", "Back": "はだぎ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "果して", "Back": "はたして", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "鉢", "Back": "はち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "×", "Back": "ばつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発揮", "Back": "はっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発射", "Back": "はっしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発想", "Back": "はっそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発電", "Back": "はつでん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "発売", "Back": "はつばい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "派手", "Back": "はで", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "話合い", "Back": "はなしあい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "話し掛ける", "Back": "はなしかける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "話中", "Back": "はなしちゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "甚だしい", "Back": "はなはだしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "花火", "Back": "はなび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "花嫁", "Back": "はなよめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放れる", "Back": "はなれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "羽根", "Back": "はね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "跳ねる", "Back": "はねる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破片", "Back": "はへん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "歯磨き", "Back": "はみがき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "早口", "Back": "はやくち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流行る", "Back": "はやる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "払い込む", "Back": "はらいこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "払い戻す", "Back": "はらいもどす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "針金", "Back": "はりがね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "張り切る", "Back": "はりきる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反映", "Back": "はんえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "半径", "Back": "はんけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "判子", "Back": "はんこ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "万歳", "Back": "ばんざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "判事", "Back": "はんじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "反省", "Back": "はんせい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "番地", "Back": "ばんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "半島", "Back": "はんとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日当たり", "Back": "ひあたり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日帰り", "Back": "ひがえり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "比較的", "Back": "ひかくてき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日陰", "Back": "ひかげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引受る", "Back": "ひきうける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引返す", "Back": "ひきかえす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引算", "Back": "ひきざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引出す", "Back": "ひきだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引き止める", "Back": "ひきとめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "卑怯", "Back": "ひきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引分け", "Back": "ひきわけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "髭", "Back": "ひげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "陽射", "Back": "ひざし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "肘", "Back": "ひじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引っ掛かる", "Back": "ひっかかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "筆記", "Back": "ひっき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引っ繰り返す", "Back": "ひっくりかえす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引っ繰り返る", "Back": "ひっくりかえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引越し", "Back": "ひっこし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "引っ込む", "Back": "ひっこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "筆者", "Back": "ひっしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "必需品", "Back": "ひつじゅひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人差指", "Back": "ひとさしゆび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一通り", "Back": "ひととおり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "人通り", "Back": "ひとどおり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瞳", "Back": "ひとみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "一休み", "Back": "ひとやすみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "独り言", "Back": "ひとりごと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "皮肉", "Back": "ひにく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日日", "Back": "ひにち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "捻る", "Back": "ひねる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日の入り", "Back": "ひのいり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "日の出", "Back": "ひので", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "響き", "Back": "ひびき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "響く", "Back": "ひびく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "皮膚", "Back": "ひふ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷やす", "Back": "ひやす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "美容", "Back": "びよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "表紙", "Back": "ひょうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "標識", "Back": "ひょうしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "標準", "Back": "ひょうじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "標本", "Back": "ひょうほん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "評論", "Back": "ひょうろん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平仮名", "Back": "ひらがな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "昼寝", "Back": "ひるね", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "広げる", "Back": "ひろげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "広さ", "Back": "ひろさ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "広場", "Back": "ひろば", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "広々", "Back": "ひろびろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "広める", "Back": "ひろめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "便箋", "Back": "びんせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "瓶詰", "Back": "びんづめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "風船", "Back": "ふうせん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不運", "Back": "ふうん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殖える", "Back": "ふえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "深まる", "Back": "ふかまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不規則", "Back": "ふきそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "普及", "Back": "ふきゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "付近", "Back": "ふきん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "拭く", "Back": "ふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "副詞", "Back": "ふくし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "複写", "Back": "ふくしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "複数", "Back": "ふくすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "含める", "Back": "ふくめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "膨らます", "Back": "ふくらます", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "膨らむ", "Back": "ふくらむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不潔", "Back": "ふけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "更ける", "Back": "ふける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "符号", "Back": "ふごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夫妻", "Back": "ふさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塞がる", "Back": "ふさがる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "塞ぐ", "Back": "ふさぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無沙汰", "Back": "ぶさた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "武士", "Back": "ぶし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "部首", "Back": "ぶしゅ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "襖", "Back": "ふすま", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "附属", "Back": "ふぞく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蓋", "Back": "ふた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "不通", "Back": "ふつう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物騒", "Back": "ぶっそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "船便", "Back": "ふなびん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "部品", "Back": "ぶひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "吹雪", "Back": "ふぶき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "父母", "Back": "ふぼ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "踏切", "Back": "ふみきり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "麓", "Back": "ふもと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "増やす", "Back": "ふやす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "殖やす", "Back": "ふやす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "振り仮名", "Back": "ふりがな", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "振舞う", "Back": "ふるまう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "風呂敷", "Back": "ふろしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "噴火", "Back": "ふんか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分解", "Back": "ぶんかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文芸", "Back": "ぶんげい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文献", "Back": "ぶんけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "噴水", "Back": "ふんすい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分数", "Back": "ぶんすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文体", "Back": "ぶんたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分布", "Back": "ぶんぷ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文房具", "Back": "ぶんぼうぐ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "文脈", "Back": "ぶんみゃく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分量", "Back": "ぶんりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分類", "Back": "ぶんるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "閉会", "Back": "へいかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平気", "Back": "へいき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "並行", "Back": "へいこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平日", "Back": "へいじつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "兵隊", "Back": "へいたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平凡", "Back": "へいぼん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "平野", "Back": "へいや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "凹む", "Back": "へこむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "隔てる", "Back": "へだてる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "別荘", "Back": "べっそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "別々", "Back": "べつべつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "編集", "Back": "へんしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "便所", "Back": "べんじょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "望遠鏡", "Back": "ぼうえんきょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方角", "Back": "ほうがく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "箒", "Back": "ほうき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方言", "Back": "ほうげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "坊さん", "Back": "ぼうさん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "防止", "Back": "ぼうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方針", "Back": "ほうしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "包装", "Back": "ほうそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "法則", "Back": "ほうそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "包帯", "Back": "ほうたい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "膨大", "Back": "ぼうだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "庖丁", "Back": "ほうちょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方程式", "Back": "ほうていしき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "防犯", "Back": "ぼうはん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "方面", "Back": "ほうめん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "坊や", "Back": "ぼうや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "放る", "Back": "ほうる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "朗らか", "Back": "ほがらか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "牧場", "Back": "ぼくじょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "牧畜", "Back": "ぼくちく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "保健", "Back": "ほけん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "募集", "Back": "ぼしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "干す", "Back": "ほす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "北極", "Back": "ほっきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "坊っちゃん", "Back": "ぼっちゃん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "堀", "Back": "ほり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "掘る", "Back": "ほる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "彫る", "Back": "ほる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盆", "Back": "ぼん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盆地", "Back": "ぼんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本部", "Back": "ほんぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "本来", "Back": "ほんらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "枚数", "Back": "まいすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "毎度", "Back": "まいど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巻く", "Back": "まく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蒔く", "Back": "まく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "撒く", "Back": "まく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "枕", "Back": "まくら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "曲げる", "Back": "まげる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "摩擦", "Back": "まさつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混ざる", "Back": "まざる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交ざる", "Back": "まざる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混じる", "Back": "まじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交じる", "Back": "まじる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "混ぜる", "Back": "まぜる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "交ぜる", "Back": "まぜる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "又は", "Back": "または", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "待合室", "Back": "まちあいしつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "待ち合わせる", "Back": "まちあわせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "街角", "Back": "まちかど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真っ暗", "Back": "まっくら", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真っ黒", "Back": "まっくろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真っ青", "Back": "まっさお", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真っ先", "Back": "まっさき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真っ白", "Back": "まっしろ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "祭る", "Back": "まつる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "窓口", "Back": "まどぐち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "纏まる", "Back": "まとまる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "纏める", "Back": "まとめる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "真似る", "Back": "まねる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "間も無く", "Back": "まもなく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "円い", "Back": "まるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "稀", "Back": "まれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "回り道", "Back": "まわりみち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "満員", "Back": "まんいん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "満点", "Back": "まんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見送る", "Back": "みおくる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見下ろす", "Back": "みおろす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見掛け", "Back": "みかけ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "三日月", "Back": "みかづき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "岬", "Back": "みさき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "店屋", "Back": "みせや", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見出し", "Back": "みだし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "道順", "Back": "みちじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見付かる", "Back": "みつかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見付ける", "Back": "みつける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見直す", "Back": "みなおす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見慣れる", "Back": "みなれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "醜い", "Back": "みにくい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "実る", "Back": "みのる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "身分", "Back": "みぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見本", "Back": "みほん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "見舞う", "Back": "みまう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "未満", "Back": "みまん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名字", "Back": "みょうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "ミリ", "Back": "（メートル）", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "診る", "Back": "みる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "民間", "Back": "みんかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "民謡", "Back": "みんよう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "向う", "Back": "むかう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "剥く", "Back": "むく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無限", "Back": "むげん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無地", "Back": "むじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蒸し暑い", "Back": "むしあつい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "矛盾", "Back": "むじゅん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蒸す", "Back": "むす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "無数", "Back": "むすう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "紫", "Back": "むらさき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "群れ", "Back": "むれ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "姪", "Back": "めい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名作", "Back": "めいさく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名刺", "Back": "めいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名詞", "Back": "めいし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名所", "Back": "めいしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "命ずる", "Back": "めいずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "迷信", "Back": "めいしん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "名物", "Back": "めいぶつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "銘々", "Back": "めいめい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目上", "Back": "めうえ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "恵まれる", "Back": "めぐまれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "巡る", "Back": "めぐる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目指す", "Back": "めざす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目覚し", "Back": "めざまし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目下", "Back": "めした", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目印", "Back": "めじるし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目立つ", "Back": "めだつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目安", "Back": "めやす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "免税", "Back": "めんぜい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面積", "Back": "めんせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面接", "Back": "めんせつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "面倒臭い", "Back": "めんどうくさい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "儲かる", "Back": "もうかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "儲ける", "Back": "もうける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "申し訳ない", "Back": "もうしわけない", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "木材", "Back": "もくざい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "目次", "Back": "もくじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "潜る", "Back": "もぐる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "餅", "Back": "もち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "元々", "Back": "もともと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物置", "Back": "ものおき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物語る", "Back": "ものがたる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物差し", "Back": "ものさし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "物凄い", "Back": "ものすごい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "揉む", "Back": "もむ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "燃やす", "Back": "もやす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "催し", "Back": "もよおし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "盛る", "Back": "もる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "問答", "Back": "もんどう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜間", "Back": "やかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "薬缶", "Back": "やかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役者", "Back": "やくしゃ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役所", "Back": "やくしょ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "訳す", "Back": "やくす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役人", "Back": "やくにん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "薬品", "Back": "やくひん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "役目", "Back": "やくめ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "火傷", "Back": "やけど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夜行", "Back": "やこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "矢印", "Back": "やじるし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "薬局", "Back": "やっきょく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "家主", "Back": "やぬし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破く", "Back": "やぶく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "破れる", "Back": "やぶれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "軟らかい", "Back": "やわらかい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "遊園地", "Back": "ゆうえんち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夕刊", "Back": "ゆうかん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "友好", "Back": "ゆうこう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "郵送", "Back": "ゆうそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夕立", "Back": "ゆうだち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "夕日", "Back": "ゆうひ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "悠々", "Back": "ゆうゆう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "有料", "Back": "ゆうりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "浴衣", "Back": "ゆかた", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "湯気", "Back": "ゆげ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "輸血", "Back": "ゆけつ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "輸送", "Back": "ゆそう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "油断", "Back": "ゆだん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "湯飲み", "Back": "ゆのみ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "緩い", "Back": "ゆるい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "溶岩", "Back": "ようがん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "容器", "Back": "ようき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "用語", "Back": "ようご", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要旨", "Back": "ようし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幼児", "Back": "ようじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "容積", "Back": "ようせき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幼稚", "Back": "ようち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "幼稚園", "Back": "ようちえん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "用途", "Back": "ようと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "洋品店", "Back": "ようひんてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "養分", "Back": "ようぶん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "羊毛", "Back": "ようもう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漸く", "Back": "ようやく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "要領", "Back": "ようりょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欲張り", "Back": "よくばり", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余計", "Back": "よけい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "汚す", "Back": "よごす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寄せる", "Back": "よせる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "余所", "Back": "よそ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "四つ角", "Back": "よつかど", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "酔っ払い", "Back": "よっぱらい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "予備", "Back": "よび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呼び掛ける", "Back": "よびかける", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "呼び出す", "Back": "よびだす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蘇る", "Back": "よみがえる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "因る", "Back": "よる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慶び", "Back": "よろこび", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "慶ぶ", "Back": "よろこぶ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "来日", "Back": "らいにち", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "落第", "Back": "らくだい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "欄", "Back": "らん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "乱暴", "Back": "らんぼう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "理科", "Back": "りか", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "利害", "Back": "りがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "略す", "Back": "りゃくす", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "流域", "Back": "りゅういき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "寮", "Back": "りょう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "両側", "Back": "りょうがわ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "漁師", "Back": "りょうし", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "領事", "Back": "りょうじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "領収", "Back": "りょうしゅう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "臨時", "Back": "りんじ", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "留守番", "Back": "るすばん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "例外", "Back": "れいがい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "零点", "Back": "れいてん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "冷凍", "Back": "れいとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "列島", "Back": "れっとう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "煉瓦", "Back": "れんが", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "連合", "Back": "れんごう", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "蝋燭", "Back": "ろうそく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "録音", "Back": "ろくおん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "論ずる", "Back": "ろんずる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "和英", "Back": "わえい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分る", "Back": "わかる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "分かれる", "Back": "わかれる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "若々しい", "Back": "わかわかしい", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "湧く", "Back": "わく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "詫びる", "Back": "わびる", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "和服", "Back": "わふく", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割算", "Back": "わりざん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割と", "Back": "わりと", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "割引", "Back": "わりびき", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "椀", "Back": "わん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{"Front": "碗", "Back": "わん", "Tags": [], "Deck": "n2-vocab-kanji-hiragana"},
{}]
